YASH TULSIANI

CONTACT

➡ hello@ytulsiani.com

ytulsiani.com

630-217-3889

in ytulsiani

ytulsiani

SKILLS

Languages: Java, Python, Bash, Go, JavaScript, C, Assembly, SQL

Technologies: Cloud Foundry, Chef, Openstack, Concourse CI, AWS, GCP, Heroku, Unity, Android Studio, Pivotal Tracker, Jira

Frameworks and Libraries: NodeJS.

Angular, JavaFX, OpenCV

Concepts: Agile, Continuous Integration, Automated Testing, Test Driven Development, Pair Programming, Platform as a Service, Infrastructure as Code

ACTIVITIES

Georgia Tech Communications Created content for Georgia Tech's social media platforms including their official Facebook, Instagram, Twitter, and Snapchat. Content included photos, videos, graphics, and articles that Georgia Tech used to promote campus life.

GreyHat Infosec

Used tools like Metasploit and Wireshark to see how penetration testing is done in the field by deploying vulnerable Linux VMs on my system.

Vibha · President

Helped start a Georgia Tech chapter for an organization raising funding and awareness for education for children in developing countries. Led club of 15 volunteers to host multiple successful awareness events and campaigns that raised thousands of dollars.

Tech The Halls · Vice President of Marketing Worked in executive board for an organization promoting inner-city education through connections. Responsible for finding innovative ways to increase mentor, student, and corporate sponsor awareness. Developed website for the club on bootstrap located at techthehalls.gtorg.gatech.edu.

FouroFour Co · Visual Artist Worked in creating visual content for local Atlanta brands to market their company and products.

Atlanta Humane Society

Volunteered at a humane society in dog rehabilitation and adoption center. Took photos of the adoptions animals and managed their website with new animals.

EDUCATION

Georgia Institute of Technology B.S. Computer Science August 2015 - May 2019 Dean's List, GPA: 3.18

EMPLOYMENT

Atlanta, GA Aug. 2018 to Current

Mailchimp Systems Engineering Intern

• Worked on an internal datacenter management tool to support internal and production applications

- Migrated RPC system from Apache Thrift to gRPC using Python

Pivotal Software

San Francisco, CA May 2018 to Aug. 2018

Software Engineering Intern

- Worked on a release integration system supporting open source Cloud Foundry (my work is publicly available on GitHub)
- Improved the reliability of Cloud Foundry's flakiest tests in Go
- Created CI pipelines to improve the agility of component teams deploying on the platform

Ultimate Software

Weston, FL May 2017 to Aug. 2017

Software Engineering Intern

- Worked in a devops role for Platform as a Service team supporting Pivotal Cloud Foundry
- Developed pipelines for continuous integration and automation for tasks such as SQL auto-recovery and backup on critical user data
- Migrated Chef deployments to Bosh with Ruby and Python to speed up deployment time for development teams
- Created tools to manage virtual machines on Openstack

The Home Depot

Atlanta, GA

Software Engineering Intern

May 2016 to Aug. 2016

- · Developed Proof of Concept allowing for the development of an integrated backend over multiple store fronts with Javascript and Angular to allow Home Depot to have a single interface for multiple store fronts
- · Helped decrease content deployment time from days to hours

PhD Founders Founder

Schaumburg, IL

Sept. 2014 to Feb. 2017

- · Started a tutoring company to provide low cost tutoring to over 30 students ranging from first grade to college
- Managed 3 employees and developed a sustainable business plan

PROJECTS

Computer Science Creativity

Wrote a Medium article discussing the benefits of having a creative hobby in computer science. The article was featured on multiple tech news sites and blogs, including the front page of Hacker News. The article is published at bit.ly/csCreativity.

Undergraduate Research: iTrans

Implemented machine learning algorithms in Python connected to a MySQL database to predict bus arrival and departures for Georgia Tech's busing system. These algorithms will be used to provide accurate readings for the campus busing arrival estimator API.

Developed **Unity application** as a proof of concept for an audio centric software and hardware suite to help filmmakers focus on their work without having to micromanage their crew. Details on the project, including demo videos are available at github.com/ytulsiani/Audio-AD.

Developed Game Boy Advance game in C. The game is similar to the classic game Frogger in the sense you must avoid enemies and reach to the other side before losing a certain number of lives. The code for this game is available at github.com/ytulsiani/Buzz-Hop.

Developed website to raise money for the ACLU that generates gifs with an image uploaded by the user. Software used to build this includes NodeJS, Python, and OpenCV. Website is live at bit.ly/2uxzaEW and the code is available at github.com/ytulsiani/Trump-WWE.